Renat Ibragimov

software engineer, web developer

Mobile:

+79374834304

E-mail:

renat@aomega.co

Skype:

ex.tenebris

Linkedin:

renat-ibragimov

Github:

http://github.com/mpakus

Portfolio:

http://aomega.co

Job type:

remote, full time, contractor, part-time or relocation

Hi, my name is Renat.

I'm a full stack web developer with over 16 years of professional experience. Focus on sustainable web application architecture using Ruby on Rails, modern JavaScript and responsive HTML/CSS.

My main specialization is Backend and Frontend for web applications.

- I'm a creative and results motivated developer with a lot of experience in remote and contract work
- Extensive experience in web application development
- Good expertise in using Ruby/Rails on a production Linux environment
- · Outstanding knowledge of SQL
- Amazing ability to work on a very technical team who have deep knowledge of Linux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, SQL
- Remarkable ability to multi-task and adapt to changes quickly

Skills

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Minitest, Capybara, Capistrano, JavaScript (ES6, Flow, TypeScript), CoffeeScript, ReactJS (MobX, Functional Components, Hooks, Context), Svelte, Jest, Enzyme, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, GIT, Ansible, AWS, Heroku. Interested in Elixir and Clojure languages.

Work experience

Full-Stack Developer (Independent Contractor, Consultant) at **SMS360.com** (USA, Remote), OCT 2019 – ...

Platform to manage environmental health and safety (EHS), fleet safety, and DOT as well as OSHA compliance programs – https://sms360.com

- Wrote documentation for the project in Wiki
- Setup code review, pull request and git naming process
- Increased code coverage from 0.1 to 0.6
- Setup code quality tools like Rubocop and Brakeman
- Setup Elastic Beanstalk deployment and RDS for couple of AWS EC2 services
- Updated Ruby from 2.4.4 to 2.6
- Updated Ruby on Rails from 4.2.10 to 5.2
- Moved all CoffeeScript codebase to JavaScript
- Build new flexible permission system instead of CanCan roles uses ACL features, Architecture, migrations, UI
- Architecture and Documentation for Form Builder
- Bug fixes, new features

Senior Full Stack Developer at **OnPloy.com** (Australia, Remote), MAR 2018 – APR 2020

Product helps to Search, Connect and Hire Software Engineers in Australia – https://onploy.com

- Platform for Hirers to track opportunities for IT tech Candidates (Ruby on Rails 5, PostgreSQL, Webpack, React, Flow, Jest, AWS)
- Messaging Platform between Hirer and Candidate
- Career Expansion v2
- Hong Kong version of service, multitenant, I18n localization
- New Features and bug fixes
- · Code review and release management

Senior Full Stack Developer at **Show-Score** (US, Remote), JUN 2017 – DEC 2018 Show-Score is Rotten Tomatoes for Broadway theaters - https://show-score.com

- New features for Promotions, Games and Ticketing system (Ruby on Rails 4, PostgreSQL, Rubocop, RSpec, CoffeeScript)
- Membership subscription with Stripe integration, recurrent subscription, expiration, webhooks
- SMS service with NEXMO integration, webhooks, inbound SMS logic

Lead Backend Developer at **Coins.tech** (Russia, Remote), JUL 2017 – MAY 2018 Tool to keep track of cryptocurrency investments – http://coins.tech

- Application Architecture, Database structure (Ruby on Rails 5 API, PostgreSQL, InfluxDB, Redis, Sidekiq, JWT, Financial Daemon, Parsing Bots)
- High-load optimization (PG indexes, cache, InfluxDB migration, background daemons, microservices architecture)
- Infrastructure setup, Dedicated servers and Continuous Integration with Gitlab + GitlabCI then migrated to Github + CircleCI + AppSignal
- API & Code Auto Documentation, contributed into the open source Dox gem
- Code tests ration is 1:3.3
- Bittrex, Poloniex, Bitfinex, Bitstamp, Kraken, EXMO, GDAX around 30 markets integration, released Node.js npm server for CCXT
- Code Review, Github Pull Requests and agile workflow for team.

Senior Ruby Developer at **TidyHQ** (Australia, Remote), MAR 2016 – MAY 2017 Online management tool (PaaS, CRM, ERP, eCommerce) – https://tidyhq.com

- Architecture and test coverage improved (Ruby on Rails 4, MySQL, Resque, Rubocop, RSpec, Cucumber)
- · SMS API integration with Twilio, Clicksend
- Dropbox add-on, backup and two-way synchronization
- New recurrent Sessions (regular scheduled Events)
- E-mails redesign and tests with Litmus.com and mjml, premailer
- Integration of Internal File Storage (Amazon S3) with visual text editor CKEditor (JavaScript)
- New Activity Feed v.2
- New Meetings v.2
- Backend for Referral & Reward systems
- Prepared and mentored Webpack + React + MobX part
- Improvements and code coverage for new React Contacts app (Ruby on Rails 4, MySQL, Webpack, React, TypeScript, Jest, Enzyme)
- Meetings, Events, Storage, Archive converted to add-on Apps

· Improved Membership address registration

Others:

- Senior Full Stack developer at MyCleaner (Germany, Remote) OCT 2015 FEB 2016, https://mycleaner.com
- Senior Backend Developer & Consultant at UraMedia (Russia, Remote) FEB 2016
 JUL 2016, https://likes.ru
- Senior Full Stack developer at Pick-a-paw (Canada, Remote), MAR 2015 FEB 2016, https://pickapaw.com
- Senior Full Stack developer at CleverPoint.co (USA, Remote), SEP 2015 DEC 2015, http://cleverpoint.co
- Full Stack Ruby developer at EVRONE (Russia, Remote), DEC 2014 MAR 2015, http://www.evrone.com
- Founder of aömega outsourcing agency, DEC 2012 MAR 2015 http://aomega.co
- Senior web-developer at **MetaMedia** (UK, Thailand, Office full time), 2012 2012
- Senior intranet developer at **George & Lou Co.** (Canada, Thailand, Office full time), 2010 2012, http://pureanco.com
- Lead developer at BESTWEB ltd. (Russia, Office full time), 2004-2010, http://www.bestweb.ru
- MSSQL Database administrator at **Faberlic**, C++ (MFC) desktop developer

Open sources gems

https://github.com/mpakus/malina - Rails Engine UI for browsing sent emails

https://github.com/mpakus/uniqable – Unique and random token for ActiveRecord models

https://github.com/mpakus/ccxt-server - Crypto currency Markets Node.js CCXT REST Server, npm package

https://github.com/mpakus/comandor - Service object realization (Interactor, Command)

https://github.com/mpakus/ams_types - Types system for ActiveModel::Serializer

https://github.com/mpakus/phraser - Uniq phrases (tokens) generator

https://github.com/mpakus/mint-money – Human money arithmetics

<u>https://github.com/mpakus/mint-fixer_currency</u> – Exchange rates for Mint::Money

Mentor and community leader

http://ufacode.ru - local developers community

https://github.com/ufacode/ - personal mentor for junior developers

Contributed to Open Source

https://github.com/CultivateLabs/storytime

https://github.com/ivaldi/brimir

https://github.com/Tolia/sharing_counter

https://github.com/jashmenn/activeuuid

https://github.com/lml/commontator

https://github.com/radar/forem

Education

1998 – 2004 Ufa State Aviation Technical University specialized Software Engineer.